(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
HARDY: This is Earth cargo ship C982 on course and on schedule.
这里是地球货船C982, 正按预定航线预定时间航行
We shall be entering hyperspace in 50 seconds.
我们将在50秒后进入超空间
(COUNTER CLICKING)
(SIGHING)
- You know what I'd like? - What?
- 你知道我喜欢什么吗? - 什么
Job on one of those luxury space liners.
在那些豪华太空航线上工作
First Officer on the Mars-Venus cruise, that'd suit me.
比如火星到金星的船上当个大副, 那就很适合我
(CHUCKLING) You can keep it.
你就继续做梦吧
Spit and polish, cocktail parties and all those passengers?
衣着光鲜, 鸡尾酒会, 跟乘客们聊聊天
Gold braid uniform, beautiful stewardesses?
金色纹路的制服, 漂亮的空姐?
Yeah, I'd take that anytime.
嘢, 那样的地方我随时都想去
You'll more likely wind up pushing a battle cruiser.
你最终还是更有可能开一艘战斗舰
There's not going to be an interplanetary war.
但并不会有星际战争啊
Didn't you see the videocast last night?
你看了昨晚的视频直播了吗?
The president of the Earth's government
地球政府的总统
deplores the Draconian attack on two of Earth's cargo vessels.
对于龙族袭击地球两艘货船的事感到痛心
Look, they steal a few of our cargoes, we steal a few of theirs.
看, 他们偷走了一些我们的货船, 我们也偷走他们了
It'll all blow over.
这一切都会过去的
Right. We're ready for the jump.
是. 我们马上要跃迁了
Preparing to enter hyperspace at 22-09-72, 2540 ESP.
准备进入超空间, 坐标 22-09-72, 2540 ESP.
- Right. - Right.
- 核实无误 - 核实无误
Hey, look. A ship.
嘿, 快看, 一艘船
- STEWART: That thing's not a ship. - It's gonna hit us.
- 那可不是一艘船 - 但要撞到我们了
Pulling out of hyperspace now in 22-13-72 7240.
赶紧从超空间拉出来, 坐标 22-13-72 7240.
Phew! That was a close thing.
呼, 刚才好险
- HARDY: It vanished, it just vanished. - You'd better report it.
- 它不见了, 它刚刚不见了 - 你最好上报上去
Mysterious object sighted during hyperspace transition.
在进入超空间后目击到神秘物体
Object resembles a large box with flashing light on top.
外形类似一个很大的箱子, 顶部闪着灯
Object disappeared before collision.
在即将碰撞的时候该物体消失了
Present whereabouts unknown.
该物体的当前位置未知
(SIGHING)
Well, I'm never going in that thing again.
我可再也不进去那里了
Oh, come on, Jo, be reasonable.
哦, 得了, Jo, 理性一点
Only you could manage to have a traffic accident in space.
只有你能在太空当中制造一场交通事故
- Well, we didn't hit it, did we? - Didn't we? Where's this then?
- 不过, 我们并没有装上, 对吧? - 没有? 那这里是哪里?
Well, by a rather brilliant last-minute course correction,
这个嘛, 在最后紧急关头, 凭着我漂亮的修正
I've managed to materialise the TARDIS inside the spaceship.
我把 TARDIS 开到了这艘飞船的内部
But to avoid hitting it,
但为了避免跟它相撞
I've had to make a random jump back into normal space.
我不得不跳回了普通空间
Terrific, but what do we do now?
挺棒, 但我们现在做什么
Well, if I'm to get us back to Earth, I'd better find out where we are.
唔, 如果我要把我们带回地球, 我最好要先搞清楚我们在哪里
I'll just go and check the instruments.
我去检查一下仪器
- Hmm, they're carrying bulk flour. - DOCTOR: What?
- 他们在运送散装面粉 - 什么?
They're carrying a cargo of bulk flour.
他们带了一船的散装面粉
(HIGH-PITCHED BLEEPING)
- Doctor? - Well, I think I know where we are.
- 博士? - 我想我知道我们在哪儿了
I've got a pretty good idea about when.
而且对于我们在何时也基本清楚了
- Come and take a look at this. - A look at what?
- 过来看一下这个 - 看看什么?
That.
那个
Well, it's just a spaceship, Jo.
只是一艘飞船, Jo
Now, I reckon we must be somewhere in the 26th century.
现在我估计我们肯定在26世纪的某处
Well, interstellar travel's pretty routine by now.
在这个时代, 星际旅行已经比较普遍了
A moment ago, it seemed to change shape.
就此刚才, 它好像在变形
- Hmm? - It was when I heard that noise.
- 嗯? - 就是那时我听到那个声音的
Didn't you hear it?
你没有听到吗?
Well, I did hear something but very faintly.
我也听到点声音, 但比较微弱
Come on, Jo. Let's go and find the crew.
这儿来, Jo. 我们去找找船员
I want to find the exact date for my calculations.
我想去问问具体的日子, 看看我的计算对不对
- Doctor! It's coming straight at us! - DOCTOR: What?
- 博士, 它朝我们直接过来了 - 什么?
HARDY: You won't believe this.
你不会相信的
- Now what? - Maybe it's a wreck.
- 现在怎么办? - 可能是艘废船
Try and make contact. They may need help.
试着联系一下, 他们可能需要帮助
This is Earth cargo ship C982 in close proximity to you.
我们是地球货船C982, 就在你们旁边
Do you read me? Do you read me?
你们能听到吗? 你们能听到吗?
(WHITE NOISE OVER RADIO)
- Try again. - Do you read me?
- 再试试  - 你们能听到吗?
Are you in need of assistance?
你们是否需要协助?
(WHITE NOISE OVER RADIO)
It's a weird-looking crate.
这箱子看起来真奇怪
(HIGH PITCHED BLEEPING)
Draconians!
龙族人!
STEWART: This close to Earth?
离地球这么近他们也敢?
- HARDY: They're going to attack us! - STEWART: Get the blasters.
- 他们要攻击我们 - 去拿枪
HARDY: You can't take on a battle cruiser!
你没法打赢一艘战斗巡航舰
Get the blasters!
去拿枪!
Emergency, emergency, red alert.
紧急情况, 紧急情况, 红色警报
This is Earth cargo ship C982
这里是地球货船C982
on coordinate 8972/6483.
目前在坐标8972/6483
We are under attack by a Draconian battle cruiser, galaxy class,
我们正被一艘龙族战斗巡航舰攻击, 星系级
equipped with neutronic missiles.
装备有中子导弹
Emergency, emergency!
紧急情况, 紧急情况
That's interesting.
有点意思
- They must be going to do a linkup. - What for?
- 他们肯定要建立连接了 - 为了什么
Well, the two ships are joined together by a sort of tunnel,
两艘船用某种通道连接到一起
you see, with two airlocks.
两个减压舱连在一起
Well, then they equalise the pressure
allowing the crew to move from one ship to the other
然后将两边的气压调到一致, 船员就可以从一艘船到另外一艘船
without the use of space suits.
而不用穿太空服
Otherwise, they'd have to get all kitted up and do a space walk.
要不然, 他们就得准备全套东西, 进行太空行走
Fascinating, but let's get back to the TARDIS.
挺吸引人的, 不过我们还是回到 TARDIS 去吧
Look, Jo, don't worry. We'll be on our way soon.
Jo, 不要担心, 我们很快就回去
Now, let's go and take look at the ship's calendar.
现在, 我们这边走, 去看一眼飞船里面的日历
(HIGH-PITCHED BLEEPING)
Oh, how do you do? I'm sorry about this intrusion.
哦, 你好, 很抱歉这样闯进来
HARDY: Who are you?
你是谁!
(HIGH-PITCHED BLEEPING)
DOCTOR: I said how do you do?
HARDY: Dragons!
- 我说了你好 - 龙!
- Drop that gun. - Gun?
- 把枪扔掉 - 枪?
I haven't got a gun. This is simply my hand.
我没有枪, 这只是我的手
(GASPING) No!
不!
-DOCTOR: Jo, what's the matter with you? - He's a Drashig!
- Jo, 你怎么了? - 这是个怪物
DOCTOR: Nonsense, it's simply a man with a gun.
Now pull yourself together.
别胡说, 只是一个普通人拿了一把枪. 现在站好了
This is Earth cargo ship C982.
这里是地球货船C982
Situation, red alert.
状态, 红色警报
Draconian battle cruiser is now about to grapple.
即将遭遇龙族战斗巡航舰
They are going to lock on now.
他们就要将船对接上了
Repeat, Draconian battle cruiser about to lock on now.
重复, 龙族战斗巡航舰即将对接上我们的船
All anti-boarding procedures carried out.
所有反登船措施已经实施
Awaiting instructions. Out.
等待进一步指令. 完毕
This is the commander of the Draconian battle cruiser.
我是龙族战斗巡航舰的指挥官
We are locked onto your vessel
我们已经对接上你们的船只
and are about to board.
即将登船
If you offer any resistance,
如果你们进行任何抵抗
you will be destroyed.
你们将会被消灭
Open the hatch of your airlock.
打开你们减压舱的舱门
I found these two Dragons in the hold.
我在货舱里找到了这两条龙
But that's impossible. They... They're only just locking on.
这不可能啊, 他们才刚刚对接上
Doctor, what's happening? What's going on?
博士, 发生了什么? 什么情况?
I'm not sure, Jo. Something rather intriguing.
我不确定, Jo. 有点奇怪
If you resist, we can destroy you with our neutronic weapons.
如果你们反抗, 我们会用我们的中子武器消灭你们
If you destroy our ship, you won't get the cargo.
如果你摧毁我们的飞船, 你就得不到货物了
Oh, so that's what it's all about.
哦, 原来是为了这个
Open the hatch to your airlock
打开你们减压舱的舱门
or we shall enter your ship by force.
否则我们要采用武力进入了
- We refuse. - They can blow us to pieces!
- 我们拒绝执行 - 他们会把我们轰成碎片的
I've sent a message to Earth asking for help.
我已经给地球发信息求救了
Tell them about the prisoners.
把囚犯的事告诉他们
We have captured two of your soldiers.
我们已经抓住了你们的两个士兵
They will not survive if you enter our ship.
如果你们登入我们的船, 他们的命就不保了
- Lock them in the hold. - Move!
- 把他们关到货舱去 - 走!
- Get moving! - Emergency, emergency.
- 快走! - 紧急情况, 紧急情况
Red alert. This is cargo ship C982
红色警报, 这里是货船C982
on coordinate 8972/6483.
坐标 8972/6483
Draconian battle cruiser has now locked on.
龙族战斗巡航舰已经对接锁定我们
They are about to force entry.
我们即将武力进入
Repeat, they are about to force entry.
重复, 他们即将武力进入
(VOICE ECHOING)
But all these charges are false, Your Highness.
这些指控都是假的, 殿下
We are not attacking Draconian ships. We never have!
我们没有攻击龙族的船, 从来没有
Our soldiers have seen the Earthmen attack us.
我们士兵倒看见过地球人攻击我们
Our cargos have been stolen.
我们的货物被偷走
We are Draconians, we do not lie.
我们是龙族人, 我们不撒谎
The honour of your race is well known, Your Highness.
你们种族的名声是众所周知的, 殿下
That is why I cannot understand your actions.
这也是为什么我弄不明白你们的行动
Actions?
行动?
You attack our ships, you steal their cargoes,
你们攻击我们的船, 你们抢走他们的货物
you ignore our protests and just meet them with these counter-charges.
你忽略我们的抗议, 只是提出这些反诉
Our charges are true but yours are false.
我们的指控是真实的, 但你们的是假的
We do not attack your ships.
我们不会攻击你们的船
This is a transcript of a distress call from one of our ships.
这是有记录, 抄录自我们一艘船说发出的求救信号
"From Earth's cargo ship number C982 on coordinate 8972/6483.
"来自地球货船, 编号C982, 坐标 8972/6483
"We are under attack by a Draconian battle cruiser,
我们正被一艘龙族战斗巡航舰攻击
"galaxy class, equipped with neutronic missiles."
星系级, 配备有中子导弹
The treaty between our two empires established a frontier in space.
我们两个帝国通过协商建立了一个太空边界
We have never violated that frontier.
我们来从来没有违反过这个条约
You have invaded our part of the galaxy many times.
但你们已经数次入侵我们星系
In pursuit of your ships when they have raided ours!
We've been very patient, perhaps too patient.
我们一直很有耐性, 也许是太有耐性了
General Williams!
Williams 将军!
I take it a rescue attempt has been mounted?
我认为已经在安排营救了吧?
We've established an automatic procedure,
我们已经一套自动化过程
because of the frequency of these attacks.
因为这种攻击已经变得很频繁了
Then I suggest you go and supervise the matter.
那我建议你离开, 去监控好营救过程
There's no need.
这并没有必要
Please do as I say.
请按我说的做
As you wish, Madam President.
听您的吩咐, 总统夫人
Your general is insolent.
你的将军太无礼了
We know the hatred he has always felt for our people.
我们都知道他一直都对我们种族怀着仇恨
Long ago he caused war.
很久以前他挑起了战争
Now he wishes to do so again.
现在他还打算再来一次
He's a soldier, Your Highness, and he's angry.
他是个战士, 殿下, 而且他很愤怒
The people of Earth are angry.
地球人都很愤怒
So are the nobles of my father's court!
我父亲的王廷上那些贵族也一样!
I must ask you to take my personal appeal to your father, the Emperor.
我必须得让你把我的个人意见带给你父皇
He must put a stop to these attacks.
他必须叫停这些攻击
If Draconia has some grievances against Earth,
如果龙族对地球有什么不满
then this is not the way to deal with them.
这也并不是处理问题的正确做法
Many of our noblemen felt it was a mistake
to make a treaty with the Earthmen.
我们贵族中的许多人认为跟地球人缔结条约是一个错误
Perhaps they were right.
也许他们是对的
You attack our ships and when we protest
你们攻击了我们的飞船, 当我们提出抗议的时候
you trick us with lies and evasions.
你们又用谎言和否认来欺骗我们
I give you a final warning.
我给你们最后的警告
The path you are treading leads only to war.
你们走的这条路只会通向战争
And in that war, Draconia will destroy you!
而在这场战争里, 龙族人会摧毁你们
In there.
进去
- DOCTOR: Look... - In there!
- 你看... - 进去!
Doctor, what's happening on this ship?
博士, 这艘船现在怎么了?
Are they both mad or am I? First I see a Drashig and...
是他们都疯了, 还是我疯了? 先是我看到了一个怪物...
No, you can put that away. Bolts.
不, 你可以不用去想那个了.fixme
And why do they keep calling us Dragons?
为什么他们一直把我们叫做龙?
Well, that's the way they see us, I suppose.
哦, 那应该是他们眼中我们的样子, 我猜测
Yes, but why Dragons?
哦, 但为什么是龙?
It's got to be some non-human life form.
肯定是某种跟人不一样的生命形式
Something that they're frightened of. Dragons... Dragons.
某种他们很害怕的东西, 龙...龙...
- Yes, of course. Draconians. - What?
- 对, 当然了, 龙族人 - 什么?
Well, if this is the period that I think it is,
there are two great empires
这样, 这就是我猜测的那段时间, 有两个大帝国
spreading their way through the galaxy of the Milky Way.
把他们的版图扩大到了整个银河系
Empires? You mean like Solos?
帝国? 你是说 Solos 那个?
Jo 说的 Solos 是指第9季第3个故事 The Mutants 中的一个星球
该故事发生在30世纪的地球帝国时期
Those were the declining years of Earth's planetary empire,
那是地球帝国的衰败期
this is just the beginning.
而这还在刚兴起的时候
Now, Earth and Draconia are both been expanding, you see.
现在, 地球和龙族都在扩大版图, 你看
Colonising one planet after another,
and they're sitting on a powder keg.
殖民一个又一个星球, 他们就坐到了火药桶上
Yes, but why do they mistake us for these Dragons?
这样啊, 那他们h为什么会把我们错当成龙
No, Draconians. No, Dragons is rather an unflattering nickname.
不, 是"龙族人", "龙"只是一个不讨好的绰号
Well, you remember that sound you heard?
对了, 你还记得你听到的那个声音吗?
- Yes. - And the man that you saw with the gun?
- 是的 - 你看到的那个人带着枪?
Oh, no. No, no, what I saw was a Drashig.
哦, 没有, 没有. 我看到的是一个怪物
No, you didn't, Jo. That sound made you see what you fear most.
不, 你没有. Jo, 那个声音让你看到你最害怕的东西
- How? - Well, it shouldn't be too difficult.
- 怎么可能? - 哦, 应该也不是太难
Ultrasonics geared to stimulate the fear centres of the brain,
用超声波刺激大脑中的恐惧中心
- something like that. - How long does it last?
- 差不多就可以主动哦傲 - 可以维持多久?
How long before they see that we're just people?
多久以后他们才能看清我们只是人类?
Well, difficult to say.
这个, 不太好错
It seems to act like a, sort of post-hypnotic command.
看起来有点像是某种深度催眠
It will fade eventually, of course.
但最终会消退的, 当然了
(SIGHING) Why should anybody go to all this trouble
to make people see things?
为什么会有人会如此费劲地让别人看到其它的东西?
- Why indeed?
- 对啊, 为什么?
Well, we've got to get out of here somehow.
我们还是先得想个办法跑出去
- Doctor! - Hmm?
- 博士!  - 嗯?
- I can see the TARDIS. - Well, that's one consolation, isn't it?
- 我可以看到 TARDIS - 啊, 总算有点让人欣慰的事情, 对吧
- Try Earth Control again. - Emergency, emergency, red alert.
- 再联系一下地球控制中心 - 紧急情况, 紧急情况, 红色警报
This is Earth cargo ship C982 on coordinate 8972/6483.
这里是地球货船C982, 坐标 8972/6483
Ah! They're jamming us.
啊, 我们被屏蔽了
Well, maybe the first message got through. They'll send help.
好吧, 也许第一次的信息传过去了, 他们会派人来帮忙的
Will they? They're probably still passing memos to each other.
会吗? 他们很可能只是相互传递一下备忘录
- They'll send help. - I know what they'll do.
- 他们会派人来帮忙的 - 我可知道他们会怎么做
They'll send a note of protest to the Draconian Embassy.
他们会向龙族大使馆递交一份抗议书
By that time, we'll be finished.
到那个时候, 我们早就完了
The Government should have blown the blighters out of space years ago.
政府早就应该把那些讨厌的家伙炸出太空去
- And have another war? - What do you think this is?
- 又来一场战争? - 你觉得现在是什么?
Look, the door of our space lock is 99% durilium.
我们的减压舱门可是 99% 的硬铝合金
They're not going to get through that in a hurry.
他们一时半会没法弄穿它
DRACONIAN COMMANDER: Earth men, this is your last warning.
地球人, 这是对你们最后的警告
Surrender your cargo, and you will be unharmed.
交出你们的货物, 你们就会平安无事
Resist and you will be destroyed.
如果反抗, 你们就会被消灭
Right. Looks like battle stations. We'd better get down to the airlock.
好吧, 看来是个硬茬, 我们最好到减压舱那里去
- You're not going to fight them? - If I have to.
- 你们不打算跟他们斗吧? - 别逼我太甚
Do you have a better idea?
你有更好的主意吗?
- It's only a load of flour! - It's my cargo.
- 只不过是一堆面粉罢了 - 但这是我运的货啊
And if the Draconians want it,
但如果龙族人想拿走
it's going to cost them more than just a few threats.
不可能就凭几句话吧, 怎么也得付出点代价
And the Bureau of Population Control announced today
人口控制总局今日宣布
that the recently reclaimed Arctic areas
are now ready for habitation.
北极地区已经改造完成, 现在已经适于人类居住
As a special inducement for those willing to live
in New Glasgow and New Montreal,
最先开发的城市是新格拉斯哥和蒙特利尔,
the first two totally enclosed cities to be opened
作为一项激励措施, 最先迁移到这两座城市的家庭
the family allowance will be increased to two children per couple.
每对夫妇允许的孩子数量将提高到两个
News is just coming through of another Draconian attack
刚刚收到的消息: 又一起龙族人攻击事件
on an Earth cargo ship in space.
发生在太空中的一艘地球货船上
(INTERCOM BEEPS)
This is the third attack on an Earth cargo ship this month.
这是本月以来针对地球货船的第三起攻击
In a statement issued by the Draconian Embassy on Earth,
驻地球的龙族大使馆发布声明说
the Draconian government denies all knowledge of this
or any other attacks.
龙族政府对于本次攻击, 以及之前的攻击事件, 毫不知情
As yet there has been no official comment,
虽然目前还没有出现任何官方评论
but Congressman Brook, Leader of the Opposition, has said,
但国会议员, 反对党领袖 Brook 说
"The people of Earth will no longer tolerate these unprovoked attacks.
"地球人不会再忍受这些无端攻击
"It is time for the world government to take a stand
"地球政府应该站出来表明立场
"and issue a final ultimatum to the Draconian Emperor. "
"向龙族皇帝发出最后通碟"
(BEEPING)
I thought I ordered a complete security blackout!
我想我是下达了消息完全封锁的命令的
The news services have their own monitors.
新闻机构有他们自己的监控服务
They probably picked up the distress messages.
他们很可能采集到了求救信号
And?
怎样?
The rescue ships should rendezvous in 17 and a half minutes from now.
救援船将在17分半之后到达出事地点
It'll be too late, of course.
当然, 肯定是来不及了
All they'll find will be dead men and a gutted ship.
他们能找到的就只有死去的船员和被破坏的飞船
(HISSING)
They'll be through that door any minute!
他们马上就能穿过那个门了
Doctor, what are you doing?
博士, 你在做什么?
I'm reversing the polarity of my ultrasonic screwdriver's power source,
我在把音速起子上电源的极性翻转过来
thereby converting it into an extremely powerful electromagnet.
这样它就变成了一个极强的电磁铁
Oh. What good will that do?
哦, 那又有什么用呢?
You wait and see, Jo.
你等着看吧, Jo
Is it working?
这能行吗?
(LOCK GRATING)
Yes, I think so.
是的, 我觉得可以
- I'm going to get the prisoners. - What for?
- 我去把囚犯带出来 - 带出来做什么?
We're using them as hostages, remember?
我们可以用他们作为人质, 记得吧?
You'd better be quick about it. We haven't got much time.
你最好动作快点, 我们没有太多时间
- How is it going? - Nearly there.
- 进展怎么样 - 快好了
(LOCK GRATING)
There you are, that's it.
看到你了, 哈哈
Oh, how very embarrassing.  Good afternoon.
哦, 好尴尬啊. 下午好
- Out. - That's just where we were going.
- 出来 - 我们正打算出来呢
We're going to meet your friends.
我们去见见你们的朋友
- Come on! Get up there! - Come on, they're almost through.
- 快点, 上这里来! - 快点, 他们快打穿了
HARDY: Get in front! If your friends start shooting,
they'll get you first.
站前面去! 如果你的朋友们开始开枪, 先射死的是你们
- But they're not our friends! - You are part of their boarding party.
- 但他们不是我们的朋友! - 你们俩是他们登船小队的成员
They haven't boarded yet. They're still breaking through that door.
他们还没有登船. 他们还在切割舱门呢
- Now, try and be logical, man. - They're coming through!
- 能不能讲点理, 伙计 - 他们过来了
- Ogrons! - DOCTOR: Back to the TARDIS, Jo. Back!
- Ogrons! - 快回到 TARDIS, Jo. 回去!
Doctor! Doctor!
博士, 博士!
NEWSCASTER: Distress signals have been received
收到求救信号
from another Earth cargo ship,
来自另外一艘地球货船
reporting an attack by a Draconian battle cruiser.
信号里说被一艘龙族战斗巡航舰攻击
Rescue ships are now on their way.
救援船已经在前往的路上
(BEEPING)
There have been anti-Draconian riots in Tokyo and Belgrade,
在东京和贝尔格莱德发生了反龙族人骚乱
and the Draconian Consulate in Helsinki has been burnt to the ground.
赫尔辛基的龙族领事馆已经被烧
In Los Angeles, demonstrators burnt an effigy of you.
在洛杉矶, 示威者烧毁了一座你的塑像
(INTERCOM BEEPING)
Yes?
什么事?
They have just found the cargo ship, Madam President,
他们已经找到了出事货船, 总统夫人
- but it is not responding to signals. - And the Draconians?
- 但对于呼叫没有应答 - 那龙族人呢?
There is no sign of any Draconian ships, sir.
这里没有任何龙族飞船的迹象, 先生
- They are about to board...now. - Thank you.
- 他们现在打算登船 - 谢谢
We shall soon know what really happened.
我们很快就能知道到底发生了什么
If there's anyone alive to tell them.
-- 如果还有人活着告诉我们的话
JO: (SOFTLY) Doctor?
博士?
- Jo? - JO: Doctor!
- Jo? - 博士?
- Jo? - JO: Doctor, I'm over here.
- Jo? - 博士, 我在这里
All right, Jo, what are you doing in there?
好, Jo, 你在那里面干什么
Oh, Doctor, thank goodness, you're all right.
哦, 博士, 感谢神灵, 你没事
I thought they'd killed you.
我以为他们杀了你
Come on, come and sit down.
来吧, 过来坐下
Must have been some kind of neuronic stun gun.
肯定是某种中子击晕枪
I wonder why they didn't kill me? What exactly happened, Jo?
很奇怪他们为什么没杀了我? 到底发生了什么, Jo?
Well, they took the cargo, threw me in here and...
呃..他们把货拿走了, 然后把我扔到这里面就...
- Doctor? - Hmm?
- 博士 - 唔?
- They also took the TARDIS. - Oh...
- 他们还带走了 TARDIS - 噢...
Oh, we're stranded. What are we going to do?
哦, 我们陷入困境了. 现在怎么办?
Well, try and get the TARDIS back, of course.
当然是想办法把 TARDIS 弄回来
(JO SIGHS)
Why should the Ogrons attack this ship?
为什么 Ogrons 要攻击这艘船?
- To steal the cargo. - No. No, there's more to it than that.
- 为了偷货呗 - 不, 不, 远不仅于此
That... That sound that you heard,
那个...你听到的那个声音
it's all too sophisticated for the Ogrons.
对于 Ogrons 来说过于复杂了
- Well, they're gone now. - Yeah, the question is, where?
- 他们现在已经走了 - 对, 但问题是, 去了哪儿?
(博士跟 Jo 上一次碰到 Ogrons 是在09x01 The Day of the Daleks,
所以这次 Ogrons 这次一露面, Jo 就能认出他们了)
Hey, Doctor, last time we met the Ogrons
嘿, 博士, 上一次我们碰到 Ogrons 的时候
they were working for the Daleks, right?
他们在为 Daleks 卖命, 对不?
- Well, you don't suppose that that... - No, no, not necessarily.
- 这, 你不是想说... - 不, 不, 不一定
No, the Ogrons are mercenaries.
不, 这些 Ogrons 都是雇佣兵
Other life forms use them to do their dirty work.
其他的种族会用他们来干些脏活
Come on, Jo, let's go and find the crew.
来吧, Jo, 我们去看看能不能找到船员
Take a look at that one.
你看一下那个
Well, they're both stunned, just as I was.
嗯, 他们都被击晕了, 跟我一样
That's funny. The Ogrons have repaired the airlock door.
很有意思, 这些 Ogrons 还把减压舱们给修好了
Well, that was nice of them.
啊, 他们心肠不错啊
Well, if they hadn't, we'd have both been done for.
嗯, 如果他们不这样, 我们就都玩完了
All the air would have escaped when the ships unlocked.
他们的船一断开, 所有的空气都早跑光了
Why should they go to all that trouble?
他们为什么要费这些劲呢?
Well, maybe they've got kind hearts.
There's good in everyone you know, Jo.
这个, 也许他们本来心肠不坏. 每个人内心都有善良之处的, Jo
(JO SIGHING)
GARDINER: Earth battle cruiser to Earth cargo ship number C982.
地球巡航舰呼叫地球货船C982
We are now approaching you. Do you read me?
我们正在靠近你船, 是否听到?
- Look after them, will you? - Right.
- 照看一下他们, 可以吗? - 好的
GARDINER: Do you read me?
你们能听到吗?
Earth battle cruiser to Earth cargo ship number C982.
地球巡航舰呼叫地球货船C982
We are now approaching you. Do you read me? Over.
我们正在靠近你船, 是否听到?
Earth battle cruiser to Earth cargo ship number C982.
地球巡航舰呼叫地球货船C982
We are now approaching you. Do you read me? Do you read me?
我们正在靠近你船, 是否听到?
Prepare to be boarded. Repeat, prepare to be boarded.
准备接受登船. 重复, 准备接受登船
Do you read me? Over.
你们能听到吗? 完毕
Hello battle cruiser, battle cruiser, this is the cargo ship. Over.
你好, 战斗巡航舰, 战斗巡航舰, 这里是货船. 完毕
What is your situation?
你们当前情况怎么样?
The ship has been attacked and the cargo stolen. Over.
货船被攻击了, 货也被劫走了. 完毕
Do you have casualties?
你们是否有伤亡?
Yes, the crew are stunned, but otherwise they're unharmed. Over.
有, 船员被击晕了, 其他人未受伤害. 完毕
We shall lock on. Five seconds from now.
我们即将对接锁定, 5秒之内
DOCTOR: It's all right, Jo. We're being rescued.
没事了, Jo. 我们得救了
- What happened? - Well, don't worry, old chap.
- 发生了什么? - 别担心, 老伙计
You'll be all right now. I think...
你很快就没事了, 我想...
Draconians! They're boarding!
龙族人! 他们要上船了!
- Stewart? Who are you? - Passengers.
- Stewart? 你们是谁?  - 乘客
I see. Having a fancy dress party? What happened?
我明白了, 在开化妆舞会? 刚才什么情况?
- Dragons attacked us. - Did they get the cargo?
- 那些龙袭击了我们 - 他们劫走货物了没
- I don't know. - Yes, they took everything.
- 我不清楚 - 是的, 他们全拿走了
Including some rather valuable property of mine.
包括我个人的一些相当值钱的东西
- Well, tough luck. - Oh, thank you very much.
- 这样啊, 挺倒霉啊 - 哦, 很感谢你们
- Dragons... They attacked us. - Yes, we know.
- 那些龙...他们攻击了我们 - 是的, 我们知道了
You say you're passengers.
Isn't that a little unusual on a cargo ship?
你说你们是乘客, 这对于一艘货船来讲是不是有点不合常理啊?
Well, we're here, aren't we?
但是, 我们现在就在这里, 对不?
Where did you pick these two up?
你们在哪里捎带上他们俩的?
I don't know. I can't seem to remember...
我不知道, 好像想不起来了...
Pull yourself together! How did they get on board?
站好了! 他们是怎么上船的?
Stowaways... That's it, they were stowaways.
偷渡的... 对了, 他们是偷渡的
- They were sending messages. - That's right.
- 他们曾经往外发送信息 - 那就对了
They were helping the Dragons. They're traitors!
他们在帮助那些龙, 他们是叛徒!